<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sylvia Plath's Journals</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <p>Typewritten page<date>1959</date></p>
            <p>Edited by <name>Anita Livabella</name></p>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Bologna</publisher>
            <availability status="free">
               <p>This work is the property of the University of Bologna. It may be used freely by individuals for research, teaching and personal use as long as this statement of availability is included in the text.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>From British Library</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <pb xml:id="first"></pb>
         <head>Thursday<l/>
            <date>April 23</date>
         </head>
            <p xml:id="p1">
            As with April, spring manifests itself in joyous new<del rend="overwritten">s</del>, I am<l/>
            tired, having got up and out of <persName role="husband">Ted</persName>'s work-room by 7, after<l/>
            two weeks of <del rend="overwritten">p</del>re- and post-Guggenheim lethargy. We are transfigured,<l/>
            After a near-miss, a query and palterling over the budget and the<l/>
            lace of travel, we got it, and rounded off to the farthest thousand,<l/>
            $5,000, which seems incredibly princely to us, After an imvitation<l/>
            to Yaddo for two months in September and October, which we at first<l/>
            interpreted as a consolation prize, Guggenheim day: Friday April 10,<l/>
            </p>
         
            <lb></lb>
            <lb></lb>

            <p xml:id="p2">
            Also, <date>yesterday</date>, my second acceptance from the <objectName>New Yorker</objectName>: a pleasant<l/>
            two: <objectName>the Watercolor of Granchester Meadows</objectName> which I wrote bucolically<l/>
            "for" them, and Man in Black, the only "love" poem in my book, and<l/>
            the book-poém which I wrote only a little over a month ago at one<l/>
            of my fruitful visits to <del rend="overwritten">W</del>inthrop, Must do justice to my father's<l/>
            grave, Have rejected the <add>E</add>lectra poem from my book, Too forced<l/>
            end rhetorical, , A leaf from Ann Sexton's book would do here, She<l/>
            has none of my elenches and an ease of phrase, and an honest<gap rend="cross out"></gap>y.<l/>
            I have my <add>4</add>O unattackable poems. I think, And a joy about them<l/>
            of sorts, Although I would love more potent ones, All the <placeName>Smith</placeName><l/>
            ones are miserable death-wishes, The ones here, however grey<l/>
            (Companiona<del rend="overwritten">ll</del>e Ills, Owl) have a verve and life=-joy.<l/></p>
            
            <lb></lb>
            <lb></lb>
         
            <p xml:id="p3">
            I am still blocked sbout prose, A novel still scares me, Have<l/>
            been reading "Passage to India" for the first time and admiring<l/>
            the miraculous flow and eése of it, To have the time to show<l/>
            the plac<add rend="overwritten">i</add>ng of a red card on a black, the change of daylight<l/>
            and t<add rend="overwritten">h</add>e geography of certain hills: the blessings of the novelists<l/>
            wide untidy landscape art, It would be a certain therapy. But<l/>
            if I do some good stories, that is the way toward the mountain,<l/>
            I do not yet do them.
            </p>
         
             <lb></lb>
             <lb></lb>
         
            
            <p xml:id="p4">
            I think too much yet about What Kind they should be and Where I<l/>
            should publish them, Poems now are an evasion too, I have my<l/>
            book as such and must not take the easy way of sitting a morning<l/>
            before a poem in evasion from <add rend="overwritten">m</add>y children's Bed Book which I<l/>
            long and yet fear to begin, Part of my passiveness., If you are<l/>
            dead, noone can criti<add rend="overwritten">c</add>ize you, o<add rend="overwritten">r</add>, if they do, it doesn't hurt.<l/>
            </p>
         
            <lb></lb>
            <lb></lb>
         
            
            <p xml:id="p5">
            The "dead black" in my poem may be a transference from the visit<l/>
            = my father's grave.<l/>
            </p>
         
            <lb></lb>
            <lb></lb>
         
           
            <p xml:id="p6">
            Worked and worked with <persName>Beuscher</persName>: the skip of a week gave me courage<l/>
            and momentum: stay<add rend="overwritten">e</add>d awake the whole night before thinking over what<l/>
            I have come through and to, Concentrated on my suicide: a knot in<l/>
            which much is caught, Weary still from the absolutely deadening<l/>
            weekend in <placeName>Northampton</placeName> and <placeName>Holyoke</placeName>, The strain of <placeName>Stanley</placeName>'s<l/>
            intolerable position, How to overcome my naivete in writing?<l/>
            Read others and think hard, Never step outside my own voice,<l/>
            such as I know it,
            </p>
         
            <lb></lb>
            <lb></lb>
         
            
            <p xml:id="p7">
            I think: a <objectName type="book">Wuthering Heights</objectName> article for r<add rend="overwritten">e</add>d-shoe money, Correct<l/>
            the word in my Monitor poem, Start a poem for the bed book,<l/>
            A story on the hospital, About the affair of Starbuck <!--&--> Sexton.<l/>
            A double story, <objectName><persName>August Lighthill</persName>and the Other Women.</objectName><l/>
            Also about the children, seen through <persName>Jan</persName>'s eyes, Here is horror,<l/>
            And_all the details, Get life in spurts in stories, then the novel<l/>
            will come. A way, By the time I get to <placeName>Yaddo</placeName>, three good publishable<l/>
            stories and the <objectName>Bed Book</objectName>done<gap reason="deleted"></gap><l/>
            </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
