<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
   xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:dbo="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:frbr="http://purl.org/vocab/frbr/core#" >
   <teiHeader>
      
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sylvia Plath's Journal - 26 February 1956</title>
            <author>Sylvia Plath</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>Series I. Writings. Journals. Typescript on white paper with autograph manuscript corrections, 38 numbered leaves, 1955 Nov-1956 Apr.</edition>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Encoding</resp>
               <persName>Anita Liviabella</persName>
               <orgName>Alma Mater Studiorum - University of Bologna</orgName>
            </respStmt>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>for exercise only</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>From the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College Libraries (Massachusetts)</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc> 
      
      <profileDesc>
         <particDesc>
            <listPerson>
               <person xml:id="Oswald">
                  <persName>Oswald</persName>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="TedHughes">
                  <persName>Ted Hughes</persName>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="SylviaPlath">
                  <persName>Richard</persName>
               </person>
               <person xml:id="HamishStewart">
                  <persName>Hamish Stewart</persName>
               </person>
            </listPerson>
         </particDesc>
         <settingDesc>
            <listPlace>
               <place xml:id="Cambridge">
                  <placeName>Cambridge</placeName>
               </place>
            </listPlace>
         </settingDesc>
      </profileDesc>
      <xenoData>
         <frbr:frbr>
           
            
            <frbr:description tei:ref="#SylivaPlath" frbr:Person="https://dbpedia.org/page/Sylvia_Plath">
               <frbr:isEmbodiementOf rdf:resource="http://purl.org/vocab/frbr/core#Person"/>
               <frbr:label xml:lang="en">Sylvia Plath</frbr:label>
            </frbr:description>
            
            <frbr:description tei:ref="#HamishStewart" frbr:Person="https://dbpedia.org/page/Category:English_masculine_given_names">
               <frbr:isEmbodiementOf rdf:resource="http://purl.org/vocab/frbr/core#Person"/>
               <frbr:label xml:lang="en">Hamish Stewart</frbr:label>
            </frbr:description>
            <frbr:description tei:ref="#IsaacNewton" frbr:Person="https://dbpedia.org/page/Isaac_Newton">
               <frbr:isEmodiementOf rdf:resource="http://purl.org/vocab/frbr/core#Person">
                  <frbr:label xml:lang="en">Isaac Netwon</frbr:label>
               </frbr:isEmodiementOf>
            </frbr:description>
             
            <frbr:description tei:ref="#Cambridge" frbr:Place="https://dbpedia.org/page/University_of_Cambridge">
               <frbr:isSubjectOf rdf:resource="http://purl.org/vocab/frbr/core#Place"/>
               <frbr:label xml:lang="en">Cambridge</frbr:label>
            </frbr:description>
            
         </frbr:frbr>
      </xenoData>
   </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <pb n="03" facs="#page3"></pb>
         
         <p>19.</p>
         
         <lb></lb>
         
         <p><date>February 26</date></p>
         
         <lb></lb>
      
         <p>We walked out as the blonde one was coming in, and <persName ref="#Oswald">Oswald</persName> said<l/>
            in his dry sarcasm something about "Tell us about bone structures<l/>
            and that was the last party at Saint John's where I lost the<l/>
            red glove, as tonight I last the red bandeau which I loved with<l/>
            all the redness in my heart. Somehow these sluttish nights make<l/>
            me have a violent nunlike passion to write and sequester myself.<l/>
            I shall sequester. I don't want fo see anybody because they are<l/>
            not <persName ref="#TedHughes">Ted Hughes</persName>and I never have been made a fool of by a man.<l/>
            They are phonies, <persName ref="#HamishStewart">Hamish</persName> said: He is the biggest seducer in<l/>
            <placeName ref="#Cambridge">Cambridge</placeName>. Shall I write, and be different? Always, I grab it,<l/>
            the writing, hold it to me, defend, defend, against the flux,<l/>
            the sameness of faces. He said my name, <persName ref="#SylviaPlath">Sylvia</persName>, in a blasting<l/>
            wind which shot off in the desert behind my eyes, behind his<l/>
            eyes, and his poems are clever and terrible and lovely.<l/></p>
          
         <lb></lb>
            
         <p>Well, <persName ref="#HamishStewart">Hamish</persName>: and I took an incredibly long time walking about<l/>
            he misty streets in the moonlight and all was blurred behind<l/>
            a theatrical scrim of fog, and vague boys in black gowns staggered<l/>
            and sang. We hid behind a car, and he sild, the oroctors are<l/>
            out after me,and I kept blithering on about having faith and<l/>
            being lucky, always, if you believe in something, because you<l/>
            can walk on water. Finally, after many strange streets which<l/>
            I did not know, being far far away in a land of whisky and<l/>
            merrydown, saying <persName ref="#TedHughes">Ted</persName> to the lam<unclear rend="faded">po</unclear>osts and calding myself with<l/>
            <persName ref="#HamishStewart">Hamish</persName>, keeping saying it aloud to him, because he took<l/>
            me away safely. We came to the gates of Queens, and I wanted<l/>
            like a baby to lie down and rest, Just peace, peace, I kept<l/>
            whispering. Five boys, five late babies came up, and surrounded<l/>
            me, gently saying, what are you doing here, are you all right,<l/>
            my you smell nice, that perfume, and may we kiss you, and I<l/>
            just stood there huddled to the iron fence, smiling like a lost<l/>
            lamb and saying dear, dear, babies, and then <persName ref="#HamishStewart">Hamish</persName> was among<l/>
            them, and they climbed over and crossed the wooden bridge<l/>
            that <persName ref="#IsaacNewton">Newton</persName> once put together without bolts.<l/></p>
         
         <lb></lb>
         <lb></lb>
            
         <p><persName ref="HamishStewart">Hamish</persName> helped me up on the wall, and in my tight skirt, I<l/>
            tried to step over the spikes; they pierced my skirt, my hands<l/>
            and I felt nothing, thinking from the great distance that I<l/>
            might at last lie on a bed of solkes and not feel 1t, like<l/>
            the yoga, like celia copplestone, crucified, near an anthill,<l/>
            at last, peace, and the nails went through my hands, and my<l/>
            egs were bare to the thigh, and I was over. The stigmata, I<l/>
            sald, frozen, looking at those raw frigid hands that should<l/>
            have been bleeding. But they were not bleeding. I had gotten<l/>
            over in an act of sublime drunkenness and falth. And then we<l/>
            we<add place="above" rend="overwrite">nt</add> to <persName ref="#HamishStewart">Hamish</persName>'s room and lay on the floor by the fire and<l/>
            I was just so damn grateful for his weight on me and his mouth<l/>
            which was nice, and begged that he scold me, and he Just sald<l/>
            I wasn't a whore or a slut like I said but only a very silly<l/>
            girl and he kind of liked me and when would I learn-my lesson.<l/>
            When? When? So 1t was suddenly two—thirty, and I couldn't<l/>
            imagine being illegal, but I was, and we managed by the light<l/>
            of two matches to get downstairs, and he walked out, a dark<l/>
            lone figure against the pale white blur of snow in the dead<l/>
            quiet crescent court.<l/>
         </p>
         <lb></lb>
         <lb></lb>
         
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
