<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sylvia Plath's Journals</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <p>Fourth typewritten page<date>1956</date></p>
            <p>Edited by <name>Anita Livabella</name></p>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Bologna</publisher>
            <availability status="free">
               <p>This work is the property of the University of Bologna. It may be used freely by individuals for research, teaching and personal use as long as this statement of availability is included in the text.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>From British Library</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>

  <text>
    
      <body>
         <pb xml:id="fourth"></pb>
         <p>
            <del><gap reason="deleted"></gap></del><add place="above" rend="overwrite" seq="1">20</add>
            <date>February 26:</date><l/>
         </p>
         
         <lb></lb>
         <lb></lb>
         
         <p xml:id="p1">
            He beckoned, I came walking along the outer path, through the<l/>
            crust of snow, breaking, hearing the dry cru<del><gap reason="deleted" quantity="1" unit="character"></gap></del>nch and then<l/>
            crossing the snow fleld to him, walting for the sudden flash of<l/>
            light, the: hey, there, you stop<add place="inline">!</add> and the crack of pistols. It<l/>
            was dead quiet, and the cold snow was in my shoes and I felt<l/>
            nothing. We went through the gap in the box hedge, and <persName ref="#Hamish">Hamish</persName><l/>
            tested the ice on the river; he sald the porter chopped it,<l/>
            but it was whole, and bore us, and we crossed, free, walking<l/>
            home. And I heard the clocks striking three in the deathly<l/>
            quiet of dreaming people, and climbed the stairs somehow<l/>
            and went somehow after hot milk to bed.<l/>
         </p>
         
         <lb></lb>
         <lb></lb>
            
         <p xml:id="p2">
            And now it is today, and I slept only six hours and am weary<l/>
            and walting till next day and next to recover. I must write<l/>
            <persName ref="#Racine">Racine</persName> paper, today, dinner with <persName ref="#Mallory">Mallory</persName> (can I live) and then<l/>
            <persName ref="#Ronsard">Ronsard</persName> desperately tomorrow.<l/>
         </p>
         
         <lb></lb>
         <lb></lb>
            
         <p xml:id="p3">
            Perhaps at dinner they will be laughing at me. Well, they are<l/>
            hardly white, even though they are men. But I shall be sober,<l/>
            oh for so long. Why won't I see him agaln? But I won't. I dream<l/>
            of banging and crashing in a high wind in <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>. But I want<l/>    
            to know him sober; I want to write to him, with that kind of<l/>
            discipline and blaze. So I shall shut up and get some sleep<l/>
            tonight and tomorrow, and do so.<l/>
         </p>
         
         <lb></lb>
         <lb></lb>
         
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
