<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sylvia Plath's Journals</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <p>First typewritten page<date>1958</date></p>
            <p>Edited by <name>Anita Livabella</name></p>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Bologna</publisher>
            <availability status="free">
               <p>This work is the property of the University of Bologna. It may be used freely by individuals for research, teaching and personal use as long as this statement of availability is included in the text.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>From British Library</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <pb xml:id="first"></pb>
         <p xml:id="onlyp">
            61<add place="bottom">2</add>
            <hi rend="underline">Sunday night: <date>March 2</date>:</hi> Again, late: It will betwelve before I<l/>
            sleep. A strange, stopped day: <persName role="husband">Ted</persName> + I having morning coffee-<l/>
            black + bitter-edged, with the <surname>Bramwells</surname> in their uncomfortable<l/>
            second-flor flat, chairs turned wrond-side-to, records scattered,<l/>
            white marble free place angular + functionless. <persName>James</persName> is<l/>
            leaving for their home in <placeName>France</placeName> tomorrow. <persName role="husband">Ted</persName> met him in<l/>
            the library yesterday, a few seconds before I came into the<l/>
            periodical room from my last class of the week: I looked<l/>
            into the room throught the glass door before I opened it, saw no<l/>
            black coated <persName role="husband">Ted</persName>, pushed the door open, saw <persName>James</persName>' back in<l/>
            brown, white tweed coat then <persName>Ted</persName>, dark, disheveled + with<l/>
            that  queer eletric invisible radiance he gives off as he<l/>
            did that first day I saw him over two years ago: to think,<l/>
            irony of <gap reason="illegible"></gap>, that two years ago I was  feverishly studying<l/>
            <persName>Webster</persName><gap reason="illegible"></gap>for my supervisions (which very plays I<l/>
            am this week examinging my students on and furiously,<l/>
            desperately, taling myself into a crazy belief that I would<l/>
            somehow mange to see <persName role="husband">Ted</persName> + imprint my markineffacably<l/>
            on him before he left for <placeName>Australia</placeName> and murder his pale<l/>
            freckled mistres named <persName>Shirley</persName>. let all rivals forever<l/>
            be called <persName>Shirley</persName>. How, now sitting here in the calme clared<l/>
            livingroom where we have own ordered teas, I feel I have<l/>
            wrested chaos and despair - and all the mwasteful<l/>
            accident of life - into a rich and meaninfgful pattern -
            The light trhough this door, into the dark dum pink-walled<l/>
            dining alcove, shires to our bedroom + bright from<l/>
            his writing of poems in the swept spacious bedroom<l/>
            the chink of light through the crack in <add place="above">between</add> the doorframe<l/>
            + door betrays him to me: + suddenly all, is most, of<l/>
            that long 35 page chapter which should be - the<l/>
            evenets at leas - the core of my novel, seem cheap<l/>
            easily come-by-all that sensational jabber about<l/>
            winds + doors + walls balging away and back.<l/>
            But that was the p<hi rend="underline">sychi</hi>c equivante of the whole<l/>
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
