<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sylvia Plath's Journals</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <p>Second typewritten page<date>1958</date></p>
            <p>Edited by <name>Anita Livabella</name></p>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Bologna</publisher>
            <availability status="free">
               <p>This work is the property of the University of Bologna. It may be used freely by individuals for research, teaching and personal use as long as this statement of availability is included in the text.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>From British Library</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <pb xml:id="second"></pb>
         <p xml:id="onlyp">experience: how does <persName ref="#Woolf">Woolf</persName> do it? How does <persName ref="#Lawrence">Lawrence</persName> do<l/>
            it? I come down to learn of those two: <persName ref="#Lawrence">Lawrence</persName>,<l/> 
            because of the rich physical passion,- fields of foces - <l/>
            and the real pres<hi rend="underline">en</hi>ce of leaves and earth and beasts<l/>
            and weathers, sap-rich, and Woolf because of tha<l/>
            almost sexless neurotic lu<hi rend="underline">minous</hi>ness - The cathing<l/>
            of objects: chairs, tables + the figures on a street<l/>
            corer, and the infusion of radiance: a shimmer<l/>
            of the plasm that <hi rend="underline">is</hi> life. I can<add place="above">not</add> must not copy<l/>
            either. God knows what tone I shall strike. Close to<l/>
            a prose-poem of balanced, cadence words and <l/>
            meanings, of street-corners and lights and people, <l/>
            but not merely romantic; not marely <gap reason="illegible"></gap><l/>
            not merely a diary: not, ostensibily, autobiographic:<l/>
            in one year I must so <gap reason="illegible"></gap> this experience in<l/>
            my mind, <gap reason="illegible"></gap> it with distance, <add place="above">create</add> cool shrewd<l/>
            views of it, so that it becomes reshapen. All this - <l/>
            digression: tames, the subject: yesterday, a broken man, <l/>
            his craggy sallow face, with its look of genial <gap reason="illegible"></gap><l/>
            black lines - hair, brows wrinkles + dark grain of<l/>
            shawed beard, his bright <gap reason="illegible"></gap> balck eyes - all<l/>
            seemed broken, askew, Ted said his hand was weak<l/>
            and cold as snails. when are you leaving america?"<l/>
            I felt impelled to ask first, meaning, of course, when <l/>
            in summer. "Monday", e said. He cant work here, cant<l/>
            write here. He taled loudly, in an audible whisper if I<l/>
            wanted to quiet him, I get out of there, with the dilly<l/>
            girls listening over their periodicals. A chink opened into<l/>
            his heel: shat it must be to decide him to leave, +<l/>
            how absurdly vindicated I felt, remembering <persName ref="#Joans">Joans</persName><l/>
            mean-tuned "Why are you going? - Dont you <hi rend="underline">like</hi> it<l/>
            here?" How can James leave her? This always puzzles me,<l/>
            I need <persName ref="#TedHughes">Ted</persName> to smell + kiss + sleep + read by as I<l/>
            need bread + wine. I like <persName ref="#James">James</persName>; ine of the few men here                    
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
